Jeffrey Nguyen

 Pountain Valley
 ■ jeffdanh98@gmail.com
 □ (714)725-6316
 □ https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeffreydanh/

SYNOPSIS

Willing to learn and goal-oriented Biomedical Engineer with 4 years of academic experience involving embedded systems with medical devices and automating data analysis. Highly experienced in programming and debugging through MATLAB, Python, C++, and scripting for data analysis. Experienced in testing software systems, tracking and investigating bugs through GitLab, and automating test analysis within an Agile Scrum environment. Highly familiar with automation frameworks including Selenium.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Biomedical Engineering

California State University, Long Beach • 2020 • 3.98/4.0

Awards: Summa Cum Laude, Tau Beta Pi Scholar, Dean's Leadership Institute Awardee, Outstanding Department Baccalaureate Graduate

KEY SKILLS

Microsoft Word, Excel, Outlook, MATLAB, HTML, SAP Database, SQL, Python Automation, C++ Programming, Minitab Statistical Tool, Machine Learning Classification, Java Programming, GitLab Version Control, Test Automation

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Software Test Engineer

Applied Medical

January 2021 - Present, Rancho Santa Margarita, CA

- Design, build, and maintain test frameworks for surgical devices in an Agile Scrum environment
- Utilize test automation for data analysis from enumerated SD contents using a Python script
- Create and track defects through version control GitLab and debug C++ embedded software
- Perform software maintenance on production-released software builds after regression analysis
- Peer review and write test protocols and documents in PLM SAP and PTC Integrity workflow
- Participate in daily Scum meetings and consistently communicate with stakeholders and developers
- Mentor new hires on test protocols for scripting and manage projects for test automation

Biomedical Electronics Technician (Contract)

Nihon Kohden America

August 2020 - January 2021, Irvine, CA

- Repaired Class II patient monitoring medical devices using industrial electronic test equipment
- Performed failure investigations (FI) on \$6 million worth of stocked complaint monitoring devices
- Created documentation on failed products and updating project flow through Jira and SAP database systems
- Manually tested and troubleshooted hardware/firmware for RTOS patient monitors using built-in testing software

NIH-BUILD Research Assistant (Part-Time)

CSULB BUILD

May 2017 - May 2020, Long Beach, CA

- Utilized design of experiment to create a biomaterial scaffold and used SolidWorks to engineer a 3D printed frame
- Facilitated a team of 3 students and trained students in lab safety, procedure, and documentation
- Developed an automation script in Python to image process and perform automatic data analysis of large datasets

Summer Research Scholar (Intern)

UCSF Department of Orthopedic Surgery

May 2019 - August 2019, San Francisco, CA

- Maintained quality assurance protocol and analyzed bone remodeling at the knee joint
- Developed MATLAB and Python scripts to image process, analyze, and sort values into an Excel database
- Utilized a cloud system to manage content, protocols, and results post-experimentation